Hey. Uh, what am I holding?
>> You're holding an envelope addressed to
the Internal Revenue Service IRS in
Cincinnati. Inside there's a small plant
with broad green leaves, likely a
succulent or similar species.
>> Okay, so the Quint team just released
their latest version of their omni model
which is natively multimodel. It can
process videos, images, text and audio
and can generate streaming responses for
text and audio. This is a very
significant because the type of
applications that you can build on top
of this natively multimodel openweight
model and did I tell you it's also
multilingual in nature. Quinn and
Alibaba is becoming a significant player
when it comes to openweight models. In
fact, even for the video models, they
have best-in-class image or texttovideo
models which are very close in
performance to some of the close
proprietary models. But specifically for
Alibaba or Quinn, they're really pushing
the boundaries of multimodality. None of
the other openweight models have such
strong omni models. This is probably one
of the few openweight models that can
actually compete with some of the closed
source models. So this is building on
top of their previous work with quen 2.5
omni model but with some key
architectural differences. So the
previous version was a 7 billion model
with thinker talker architecture. This
preserved the same architecture. So you
have a thinker and talker but now both
of them are mixture of experts or oees.
Also know they're using audio
transformer for encoding the speech that
is coming in directly but it's a much
smaller footprint. So it's a 30 billion
but only 3 billion active parameters.
They also released a technical report
with this new release with some very
interesting key innovations.
Later in the video I'll show you a
couple of quick demos but let's look at
some interesting details. So this can
process text, images, audios and videos
and can deliver real-time streaming
responses in both text and natural
speech. It can process up to 30 minutes
of video at one frames per second. So
effectively you're looking at about 3
minutes of video. Now this version is
natively multilingual and it can support
text interaction in 119 languages,
speech understanding in 19 languages and
speech generation in 10 languages. So
here are the languages for speech input.
I think it covers a wide variety of
languages. Speech output is limited to
English, Chinese, French, German,
Russian, Italian, Spanish, Portuguese,
Japanese, and Korean. Although in my
test it can also generate outputs in
Arabic, in Udu and Hindi but officially
I think they are not supported in speech
output. And this is a very strong Omni
model. It's state-of-the-art for
openweight models and can also compete
closely with models like Gemini 2.5 Pro
GPD 40 or transcribe. It actually has a
dedicated
speech transcription part which you can
use standalone. and the performance is
really good. But as always, it's good to
test it on your own applications and
your own test set. Now, with the right
hardware, the speech transcription
latency can be pretty awesome. So, they
say that it can achieve latency as low
as 211 milliseconds in audio only
scenarios and a latency as low as 500
milliseconds in audio video scenarios.
And actually if you look at my demo
later in the video, the audio video
interaction does seem very natural. You
can understand up to 30 minutes of
audio. It has a pretty long context
window of over 100,000 tokens. And then
you can also control the behavior using
a system prompt. So I think even if
you're doing speech transcription, you
can provide a system prompt. So for
example, it can be just correcting
grammatical mistakes or even changing
the tone of the transcription. All the
new Quinn models are really good at
coding and they are specifically
focusing on agentic capabilities. So
Quen 3 Omni supports function calling
enabling seamless integration with
external tools and services which are
going to be critical if you want to
build agents on top of this model. Okay.
Okay. So an important part of this
release is Quen 3 Omni 30 billion 3
billion active parameter captioner. So
this is their speech transcription part
which you can use as a replacement to
something like whisper or parakeet
models from Nvidia. If you want to use
another model for speech generation, you
can just use that captioner for
transcription and then build the
subsequent layers with some other
models. In terms of the architecture, it
still follows the thinker talker
architecture very similar to the
previous version, but now both of them
are. Now the talker no longer consumes
the thinker's highle text representation
and conditions only on audio and visual
multimodal features.
This is actually critical because now
this decoupling allows other modules
like rag or function calling to
intervene on the thinker's textual
output and if desired you can supply
text to talker via controlled
pre-processing for streaming synthesis.
Another major part is since these two
are now decoupled you can have dedicated
system prompts for both thinker and
talker and you can control them
separately. Now for audio they are
introducing audio transformer which the
audio encoder is directly using and this
is trained on about 200 million hours of
audio data which provides strong general
audio representation capabilities and
actually if you look at the audio output
as well it's much more pleasant to
listen to compared to the previous
version. As I mentioned before both the
thinker and talker now are based ones.
Another interesting observation that
they have is that mixing unimodel and
crossmodel data during early stages of
text pre-training can achieve parity
across all modalities which is very
interesting. They claim the model to
have Gemini 2.5 Pro level performance
when it comes to speech recognition and
instruction following. Now, as always, I
highly recommend to test this out, but I
would say that the video capabilities or
real-time video interaction is really
pleasant. The speech is a lot more
natural compared to the previous
version. Although there are some very
interesting hallucination when you start
interacting with the model. Sometimes
the model assume that the person it's
seeing in the video is itself. So I have
seen instances in which let's say if I'm
showing it something it will think that
the model itself is that specific person
or individual and also in certain cases
I've seen that the model hallucinates
and would start generating responses in
another language. Okay so a quick look
at the benchmarks. So they claim that
Quenti Omni matches the performance of
samesized single modality models within
the Quen series and then for modality
it's best in class out of all the open
weight models and matches the
performance of closed source models. Now
the benchmarks that they have shown here
are for Omni Flash model. I'm not sure
if it's exactly the same model, but even
on the Quen official website, only the
flash version is available. There is a
demo for the openweight model on hugging
face, but overall I think the benchmark
performance are really good. Now in
terms of the openweight models, they
released three different things. One is
the quentry omni 30 billion 3 billion
active parameter instruct version. This
is the non-thinking version. Then they
have a specifically thinking version if
you want reasoning traces. And then they
also have this 30 billion 3 billion
active captioner. So this is the speech
transcription model. So let's have a
quick play with the model and then I'll
show you some code examples. Let's have
a play with the model and see how good
the experience is. For this we're going
to be using the official Quen chat. In
here they have quenti omni flash which
seems to be a proprietary version of the
omni model. So it's not exactly the
openweight model but I think the
experience is going to be very similar.
Also I don't know whether flash is a
smaller or bigger version in the
platform. You can either do voice chat
or video chat. Video chat per session
seems to be limited to 10 minutes which
is pretty long. So, we're going to try
this. And if you go to the settings, not
only there are a large number of
different voices available, but you can
also select different languages. And
when you're interacting with the model,
you can just directly change the
language. And it seems to adopt pretty
good. So, let's have a quick test. Hey,
uh, what am I holding?
You're holding an envelope address to
the Internal Revenue Service IRS in
Cincinnati.
>> Okay. What's the PO box number?
>> The PO box number is A02502.
>> Okay. Uh, and what am I holding now?
>> You're holding a book titled The Coming
Wave. What would you like to know about
it?
>> Uh, who are the authors of this book?
>> The authors of the book are Mustafa
Sulean and Michael Bascar.
>> What is this book about?
>> Ah, you're asking about that book. It's
actually called The Coming Wave. It
dives into how AI, robotics, and
nanotechnology
are about to reshape our world. The
author is Mustafa Sulean,
and he's got a pretty compelling take on
how these technologies will transform
everything from healthcare.
>> When was this book?
The book was released on June 27th,
2023.
>> Okay. Uh,
what am I holding?
>> Oh,
so you're you're holding a terrarium.
It's a glass container with a geometric
shape, possibly octagonal or docahedral
with a gold colored metal frame. Inside
there's a small plant with broad green
leaves, likely a succulent or similar
species. The terrarium is filled with
small pebbles at the bottom, creating a
drainage layer, and the plant is rooted
in soil or growing medium. Terrariums
are decorative containers that house
small plants in a controlled
environment. Often
>> mujahcoy
video audio file upload car sneak
s Auntie auntie
in
9 a
>> okay at the end it was just making of
stuff uh but in the previous
conversations um I have seen that it is
multilingual that can speak udu or Hindi
now some sometimes
it it switches the context and u it's a
really fun model to talk to
>> okay so with this model. They have
released a number of cookbooks on GitHub
which are extremely helpful. So for
example, how to do speech recognition,
speech translation, music analysis,
sound analysis, audio caption. They have
specifically cookbooks for visual
analysis, audio visual analysis, that's
realtime interaction, the type of stuff
that we looked at. Also agents and
function calling and then omni
captioner. So this is a quick example of
how to use the speech to text model. So
here they're setting up the model and
then we're going to be downloading that
specific captioner model. After that you
just need to provide the path of your
audio file. It can process up to 30
minutes of audio which is pretty great.
And I think you can also do streaming
responses. Right. So this is an audio
file. Again we have another one. Right.
The transcription part is extremely
simple. Here's an example of working
with OCR or reading text from images. So
this is the initial setup of how to set
up the model. That's the model that
we're going to be using and then we
provide the path of an image and the
text is basically I think extract the
information from this image. So it
extracted that information or he has
extract the text from the image. So this
is another image as an input and this is
the same text in latex format. So it's a
mathematical equation that the model is
able to extract. So the good thing is
that you can actually provide a system
instruction or specific information on
how you want the model to behave. That's
also going to be possible with the
speech transcription. So let's say you
can tell the model to correct any
grammatical mistakes or maybe even
rewrite the transcription in a specific
format or style that you want. I'm going
to probably create more detailed videos
of how to build on top of this model and
what type of hardware you will need. So
stay tuned for that. But I hope you
found this video useful. Thanks for
watching and as always, see you in the
next one.